Guide to the Bacon Family papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Bacon Family papers
1896-circa 1970s
SC1194
Bacon family
Bacon, Rosamond Clarke.
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964
1 Linear feet (2 boxes)
Papers related to mathematics professor Harold M. Bacon '28, MA '29, PhD '33, and his wife, Rosamond '30, MA '32, their son Charles R. Bacon, and their cousins Orrin and Harriet Dunn. Materials are related to the Dunn (Bacon) House, and Stanford history, inluding Jane Stanford and Herbert Hoover.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical notes
Harriet Dunn was a friend of Jane Stanford who operated a boarding house for young faculty on what is now White Plaza. The house was later passed down to her cousin, mathematics professor Harold M. Bacon '28, MA '29, PhD '33, and his wife, Rosamond '30, MA '32 (a co-founder of the Stanford Historical Society). In 1997, Stanford bought the house, which is now the Harold and Libby Ziff Center for Jewish Life.
Scope and Contents
Papers related to mathematics professor Harold M. Bacon '28, MA '29, PhD '33, and his wife, Rosamond '30, MA '32, their son Charles R. Bacon, and their cousins Orrin and Harriet Dunn. Materials are related to the Dunn (Bacon) House, and Stanford history, inluding Jane Stanford and Herbert Hoover.
Access Terms
Bacon, Charles; Bacon, Harold; Stanford University, Stanford Hillel.; Stanford University; Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905.; Stanford University--Faculty housing.
Collection Contents
- Holcomb, A. A., Memoirs of My Life. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Helen Stanford-writings and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bertha Stamford (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Harriet L. Dunn, internment arrangements, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bacon, Rosamond, The Bacon House, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Dunn (Bacon) House, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Orin Dunn, naturalization certificate, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letter to Nina Almond from Herbert Hoover, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Remarks at the presentation of the plaque at the Women's Clubhouse, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Dean Mary Yost commemoration, 1954 Mar 7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mrs. Harold Bacon, incoming letters, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Harold and Rosamond Bacon, LSJU land leases, 1909, 1949, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- News clippings re Herbert Hoover and Jane Stanford (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bacon, Charles R., Odyssey of a Young American: 1857 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Senior Week programs, 1902, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Journal (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Photographs, 1896-1962 (Box 1)